<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 12:11:59 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Can&#39;t Hurt Me</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 12:11:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</guid>
      <description>Author David Goggins
Summary The personal story of former Navy SEAL David Goggins who overcame traumatic experiences to become a successful soldier and athlete.
Takeaways Most people do not know what they are truly capable of and resist challenging themselves physically and mentally to stretch the limits of their potential.
Unlocking this potential requires hard work and dedicated exposure to uncomfortable experiences and pain to &amp;ldquo;callous&amp;rdquo; the mind and become mentally strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Principles</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 21:25:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_principles/</guid>
      <description>Author Ray Dalio
Summary The life and work principles of Ray Dalio, founder of investment firm Bridgewater Associates.
Takeaways An idea meritocracy is the best way to make decisions in a company. An idea meritocracy requires a commitment to truth and transparency. It can be achieved if people are open minded and ideas are evaluated based on the track record of the people who contribute them. The process can be supported by writing down and refining principles that support decision making and reflect learnings from the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Decision Making Under Deep Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_dmdu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 11:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_dmdu/</guid>
      <description>Author Vincent A. W. J. Marchau, Warren E. Walker, Pieter J. T. M. Bloemen, Steven W. Popper
Summary A review of methods and applications for decision making under deep uncertainty.
Takeaways Situations with deep uncertainty are characterized by a lack of knowledge about how future events will unfold. In complex systems, the predictability of potential outcomes is low.
When confronted with deep uncertainty, decision makers are advised to shift from a predict-then-act paradigm to a monitor-and-adapt strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Stealing the corner office</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_stealing_corner_office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 22:35:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_stealing_corner_office/</guid>
      <description>Author Brendan Reid
Summary Advice for a more strategic approach to career planning.
Takeaways Corporations typically don&amp;rsquo;t operate rationally as they consist of people who have their own benefits in mind. Career progression requires a strategic approach and tactical steps contrary to commonly accepted practices.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t be overly passionate about your ideas and rather be objective in providing optionality Embrace the changes everyone else hates Learn to promote your ideas instead of refining them without feedback Avoid a too strong focus on result orientation and instead spend time expanding your skill set Don&amp;rsquo;t be a part of the heard, and don&amp;rsquo;t gossip about peers and superiors Find big problems to solve Don&amp;rsquo;t hold peers accountable and mentor them wherever possible  Quotes &amp;ldquo;People inherently want to work with people similar to themselves and who they like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Creating a Data-Driven Organization</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_data_driven_organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 13:05:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_data_driven_organization/</guid>
      <description>Author Carl Anderson
Summary A blueprint to create a data-driven and analytics focused organization.
Takeaways Data-driven organizations are more successful and generate more value through better decision making.
For a company to be data-driven it must have the right culture and talent in place to use data effctively along the so called analytics value chain. Sponsorship from high profile positions in the organization is needed to implement a culture that values testing and experimentation to derive insights that can give a competitive advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: No rules rules</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_no_rules_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 21:52:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_no_rules_rules/</guid>
      <description>Author Reed Hastings, Erin Meyer
Summary The story of establishing a culture of freedom and resonsponsibility at Netflix.
Takeaways Netflix leadership has identified two key ingredients for a creative and innovative culture: candor and talent density. Employees are empowered to contribute their opinions and ideas. They need to get enough context about the business priorities to take ownership and make informed decisions without the burden of a buerocratic approval process. Netflix aims to attract top talent and rather pays for one highly capable employee than for ten mediocre ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: relative import</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_python_relative_import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:02:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_python_relative_import/</guid>
      <description>To test relative imports before installing a package, add the source code directory to the path.
For example, import code from a file functions.py in src/mypackage/
import sys sys.path.append(&amp;#39;/Users/username/project/src/&amp;#39;) import mypackage.functions as f </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Noise: A Flaw in Human Judgment</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 10:26:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_noise/</guid>
      <description>Author Daniel Kahneman, Olivier Sibony, Cass R. Sunstein
Summary A summary of decision hygiene practices to reduce noise in judgments.
Takeaways Noise is ubiquitous in situations that require judgment and leads to unwanted and costly variability and unfairness in decisions. The reasons for noise in judgments are manifold. People have cognitive biases and a natural preference for causal thinking that finds comfort in finding coherent explanations even if the reality is more complex and less predictable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: 21 things you may not know about the Indian Act</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_indian_act/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 14:44:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_indian_act/</guid>
      <description>Author Bob Joseph
Summary A sample of 21 of the destructive and damaging statues and policies that constitute the Indian Act.
Takeaways The Indian Act, passed in 1876, regulated and still regulates the lives of Indigenous Peoples in Canada. One of the most damaging and destructive parts of the act was the introduction of residential schools that forced children to move away from their families and forbade them to speak their home language and practice their traditional religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Agile Data Science 2.0</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_agile_data_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 16:58:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_agile_data_science/</guid>
      <description>Author Russel Jurney
Summary Instructions for a technical setup to iteratively develop practical Data Science applications.
Takeaways Many Data Science applications fail because of a missing feedback loop between the Data Scientists developing the solutions and the business stakeholders and users. To avoid a disconnect, Data Scientists need to share work in progress frequently. Software development methodolodies like Scrum need to be adapted to account for the larger uncertainty of data exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Nudge</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_nudge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 09:29:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_nudge/</guid>
      <description>Author Richard H. Thaler, Cass R. Sunstein
Summary Practical recommendations for how to design systems that support people in making the right choices.
Takeaways The design of the environment in which choices have to be made (choice architecture) often greatly influences the results, e.g. the order of food items in a cafeteria or the order of options and default values on a website. The goal of designing choice architectures should be to nudge people to make a choice that best reflects their true intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Made to stick</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_made_to_stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 14:25:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_made_to_stick/</guid>
      <description>Author Chip Heath, Dan Heath
Summary An overview of communication techniques for effective messaging of ideas.
Takeaways In order for ideas to stick with an audience they have to be framed as Simple Unexpected Concrete Credible Emotional Stories (SUCCES). If we follow the SUCCES framework, we can drill to the core of the message to know what to say (simple) and frame it in a way that helps people to pay attention (unexpected), understand and remember (concrete), believe and agree (credible), care (emotional), and act (stories).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Creativity, Inc.</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_creativity_inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:26:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_creativity_inc/</guid>
      <description>Author Ed Catmull, Amy Wallace
Summary Practical advice on how to establish and maintain a culture of creativity and innovation in an organization
Takeaways Running a large organization requires dealing with great complexity, and high uncertainty and instability. It is easy for managers to lose sight of the problems of their employees. The only way managers can avoid this is to encourage candor and open feedback, and to actively work on uncovering and understanding anything that is hidden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R: rank2score</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_r_rank2score/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:49:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_r_rank2score/</guid>
      <description>Converting a ranking into a set of normally distributed scores.
rank2score &amp;lt;- function(rank, n_total, mn = 0, std = 1, n_tied = 1) { # following the equal area method # http://node101.psych.cornell.edu/Darlington/transfrm.htm mean_rank &amp;lt;- rank / n_tied qnorm(mean_rank / (n_total + 1), mean = mn, sd = std) } </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Extreme ownership</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_extreme_ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 13:32:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_extreme_ownership/</guid>
      <description>Author Jocko Willink, Leif Babin
Summary A set of leadership principles from the Navy Seals and how to apply them to the business context.
Takeaways Successful leaders need to take ownership to the next level. &amp;ldquo;Extreme Ownership&amp;rdquo; includes owning up to mistakes, believing in the mission, and providing enough context for subordinates and supervisors. The best leaders keep their egos in check and critically assess how they can contribute to the team&amp;rsquo;s success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The goal</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>Author Eliyahu M. Goldratt
Summary The story of a plant manager who discovers the benefit of systematically assessing the processing bottlenecks instead of relying on conventional wisdom.
Takeaways Instead of relying on conventional wisdom, it is crucial to deeply reflect on the goal of an operation or organization and take a scientific and systematic approach to explore the factors (bottlenecks or constraints) that prevent us from reaching it.
The following process can serve as a blueprint to work towards achieving any goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Weapons of math destruction</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 19:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</guid>
      <description>Author Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Summary A warning of the destructive power of black-box algorithms that govern our lives.
Takeaways Algorithms and mathematical models are ubiquitously applied and drive decisions in every aspect of our lives. They, for example, determine college admissions, calculate insurance fees, and determine the content in our social media feeds. Many of the algorithms are intransparent, making it impossible to understand and challenge the results. If there is no alignment between the objectives of the models and the interest of the modeled subjects and if there is no feedback loop to improve the model over time, these &amp;ldquo;weapons of math destruction (WMD)&amp;rdquo; can cause significant harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Project to product</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:29:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</guid>
      <description>Author Mik Kersten
Summary A practical guide to developing a product focussed management framework that allows competing in the Age of Software.
Takeaways We are at the turning point of the digital revolution. Companies need to transform their business practices to effectively leverage software development and technology. Many companies realize the need for transformation but rely on management practices that are not adequate for the task.
Products differ from projects in multiple ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Mortal Engines</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_mortal_engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 20:11:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_mortal_engines/</guid>
      <description>Author Philip Reeve
Summary The fictional tale of traveling cities and their residents that battle for survival in a distant future.
Takeaways Devotion to an ideology can be a strong motivator but also a destructive force. The actions of the characters are driven by their dedication to their way of living and their role in a world that leaves little room for exploring alternative ideas.
Quotes &amp;ldquo;But he mustn&amp;rsquo;t feel sorry for them: it was natural that cities ate towns, just as the towns ate smaller towns and smaller towns snapped up the miserable static settlements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Zero to one</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_zero_to_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:01:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_zero_to_one/</guid>
      <description>Author Peter Thiel
Summary Practical advice for founders how to build a successful startup and create something new.
Takeaways Competition is a concept that has a high value in our educational system and economic thinking. The emphasis on competition leads to a uniform approach to development and only incremental improvements. Innovation and success come from avoiding competition and focusing on individual strengths and believes that set yourself apart from others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Factfulness</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:26:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Author Hans Rosling
Summary A plea to overcome the human instincts that prevent us from developing a fact based worldview.
Takeaways Knowledge of global patterns and trends is poor across demographics even though data is publicly available. Common assumptions about topics like population growth, income inequality, education and health, are not only wrong but are systematically distorted. Developments appear more negatively than they are. Reasons are a lack of statistical literacy and our instincts to generalize, blame others, and consider things without appropriate comparison frames and proportions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Straight from the gut</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 19:49:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</guid>
      <description>Author Jack Welch
Summary The life and professional career of Jack Welch, Chairman of General Electric from 1981 to 2001, described in his own words.
Takeaways Leadership requires more than the knowledge to make sound business decisions. It is equally important to establish the right culture with a focus on people that allows for differentiation and development, and that empowers everyone to contribute ideas (&amp;ldquo;boundaryless&amp;rdquo;).
Being able to react to changes trumps a well thought out longterm strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: A brief history of everyone who ever lived</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_brief_history_everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 12:36:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_brief_history_everyone/</guid>
      <description>Author Adam Rutherford
Summary A scientific view of the role that DNA plays in understanding human history, and what we can and cannot conclude when analyzing it.
Takeaways Depicting our ancestry looks more like an entagled mesh than a tree. Everyone living today shares the same group of ancestors if we go back long enough in time.
DNA influences observable characteristics in a probabilitic way. There are only a few genes that have a clear physical manifestation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo: posts and terms per taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_hugo_taxonomy_count/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 13:51:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/snippet_hugo_taxonomy_count/</guid>
      <description>Counting the number of posts and different terms per taxonomy in Hugo requires looping through all taxonomies.
{{ range $taxname, $tax := .Site.Taxonomies }} {{ $nposts := len (where $.Site.RegularPages (print &amp;#34;Params&amp;#34; &amp;#34;.&amp;#34; $taxname) &amp;#34;ne&amp;#34; nil) }} {{ $nterms := len $tax }} {{ $posttext := cond (gt $nposts 1) &amp;#34;posts&amp;#34; &amp;#34;post&amp;#34; }} {{ $termtext := cond (gt $nterms 1) &amp;#34;terms&amp;#34; &amp;#34;term&amp;#34; }} {{ $taxname }}: {{ $nposts }} {{ $posttext }} and {{ $nterms }} search {{ $termtext }}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color palettes</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/article_color_palettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/article_color_palettes/</guid>
      <description>digitalsynopsis/beautiful-color-paletts
A selection of 36 color palettes for web design or other projects. Useful to find matching colors for a consistent overall appearance.
This website uses the Water Bearer palette (#25).
#5e5656 #58668b #76b4bd #bdeaee #ebf4f6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Website with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/article_building_hugo_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:02:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/article_building_hugo_website/</guid>
      <description>This Website has been built with Hugo.
The main Hugo Website already has good documentation. The following additional resources were particularly helpful to get started and create a new template that fit my needs.
Getting started youtube/introduction_to_hugo
A series of instructional videos by Mike Dane (@mike_dane) that explain the basics of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s concepts like templates, blocks, and front-matter. Very useful to get a first exposure and a rough idea of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 18:26:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 15:44:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/about/</guid>
      <description>This site contains a collection of posts about online articles, books I&amp;rsquo;ve read and code snippets that I would like to keep for future reference.
Currently the following topics are covered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
