<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The goal</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>Author Eliyahu M. Goldratt
Summary Instead of relying on conventional wisdom, it is crucial to deeply reflect on the goal of an operation or organization and take a scientific and systematic approach to explore the factors (bottlenecks or constraints) that prevent us from reaching it.
The following process can serve as a blueprint to work towards achieving any goal.
 Identify the system&amp;rsquo;s constraint. Decide how to exploit the system&amp;rsquo;s constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weapons of math destruction</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 19:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</guid>
      <description>Author Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Summary A warning of the destructive power of black-box algorithms that govern our lives.
Takeaways Algorithms and mathematical models are ubiquitously applied and drive decisions in every aspect of our lives. They, for example, determine college admissions, calculate insurance fees, and determine the content in our social media feeds. Many of the algorithms are intransparent, making it impossible to understand and challenge the results. If there is no alignment between the objectives of the models and the interest of the modeled subjects and if there is no feedback loop to improve the model over time, these &amp;ldquo;weapons of math destruction (WMD)&amp;rdquo; can cause significant harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project to product</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:29:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</guid>
      <description>Author Mik Kersten
Summary A practical guide to developing a product focussed management framework that allows competing in the Age of Software.
Takeaways We are at the turning point of the digital revolution. Companies need to transform their business practices to effectively leverage software development and technology. Many companies realize the need for transformation but rely on management practices that are not adequate for the task.
Products differ from projects in multiple ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to one</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_zero_to_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:01:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_zero_to_one/</guid>
      <description>Author Peter Thiel
Summary Practical advice for founders how to build a successful startup and create something new.
Takeaways Competition is a concept that has a high value in our educational system and economic thinking. The emphasis on competition leads to a uniform approach to development and only incremental improvements. Innovation and success come from avoiding competition and focusing on individual strengths and believes that set yourself apart from others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Straight from the gut</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 19:49:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</guid>
      <description>Author Jack Welch
Summary The life and professional career of Jack Welch, Chairman of General Electric from 1981 to 2001, described in his own words.
Takeaways Leadership requires more than the knowledge to make sound business decisions. It is equally important to establish the right culture with a focus on people that allows for differentiation and development, and that empowers everyone to contribute ideas (&amp;ldquo;boundaryless&amp;rdquo;).
Being able to react to changes trumps a well thought out longterm strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
