<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 22:35:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Stealing the corner office</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_stealing_corner_office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 22:35:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_stealing_corner_office/</guid>
      <description>Author Brendan Reid
Summary Advice for a more strategic approach to career planning.
Takeaways Corporations typically don&amp;rsquo;t operate rationally as they consist of people who have their own benefits in mind. Career progression requires a strategic approach and tactical steps contrary to commonly accepted practices.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t be overly passionate about your ideas and rather be objective in providing optionality Embrace the changes everyone else hates Learn to promote your ideas instead of refining them without feedback Avoid a too strong focus on result orientation and instead spend time expanding your skill set Don&amp;rsquo;t be a part of the heard, and don&amp;rsquo;t gossip about peers and superiors Find big problems to solve Don&amp;rsquo;t hold peers accountable and mentor them wherever possible  Quotes &amp;ldquo;People inherently want to work with people similar to themselves and who they like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: No rules rules</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_no_rules_rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 21:52:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_no_rules_rules/</guid>
      <description>Author Reed Hastings, Erin Meyer
Summary The story of establishing a culture of freedom and resonsponsibility at Netflix.
Takeaways Netflix leadership has identified two key ingredients for a creative and innovative culture: candor and talent density. Employees are empowered to contribute their opinions and ideas. They need to get enough context about the business priorities to take ownership and make informed decisions without the burden of a buerocratic approval process. Netflix aims to attract top talent and rather pays for one highly capable employee than for ten mediocre ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Creativity, Inc.</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_creativity_inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:26:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_creativity_inc/</guid>
      <description>Author Ed Catmull, Amy Wallace
Summary Practical advice on how to establish and maintain a culture of creativity and innovation in an organization
Takeaways Running a large organization requires dealing with great complexity, and high uncertainty and instability. It is easy for managers to lose sight of the problems of their employees. The only way managers can avoid this is to encourage candor and open feedback, and to actively work on uncovering and understanding anything that is hidden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Extreme ownership</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_extreme_ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 13:32:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_extreme_ownership/</guid>
      <description>Author Jocko Willink, Leif Babin
Summary A set of leadership principles from the Navy Seals and how to apply them to the business context.
Takeaways Successful leaders need to take ownership to the next level. &amp;ldquo;Extreme Ownership&amp;rdquo; includes owning up to mistakes, believing in the mission, and providing enough context for subordinates and supervisors. The best leaders keep their egos in check and critically assess how they can contribute to the team&amp;rsquo;s success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The goal</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>Author Eliyahu M. Goldratt
Summary The story of a plant manager who discovers the benefit of systematically assessing the processing bottlenecks instead of relying on conventional wisdom.
Takeaways Instead of relying on conventional wisdom, it is crucial to deeply reflect on the goal of an operation or organization and take a scientific and systematic approach to explore the factors (bottlenecks or constraints) that prevent us from reaching it.
The following process can serve as a blueprint to work towards achieving any goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Project to product</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:29:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_project_to_product/</guid>
      <description>Author Mik Kersten
Summary A practical guide to developing a product focussed management framework that allows competing in the Age of Software.
Takeaways We are at the turning point of the digital revolution. Companies need to transform their business practices to effectively leverage software development and technology. Many companies realize the need for transformation but rely on management practices that are not adequate for the task.
Products differ from projects in multiple ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Straight from the gut</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 19:49:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_straight_from_the_gut/</guid>
      <description>Author Jack Welch
Summary The life and professional career of Jack Welch, Chairman of General Electric from 1981 to 2001, described in his own words.
Takeaways Leadership requires more than the knowledge to make sound business decisions. It is equally important to establish the right culture with a focus on people that allows for differentiation and development, and that empowers everyone to contribute ideas (&amp;ldquo;boundaryless&amp;rdquo;).
Being able to react to changes trumps a well thought out longterm strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
