<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:06:45 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Open</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_open_andre_agassi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:06:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_open_andre_agassi/</guid>
      <description>Author Andre Agassi
Summary The life and career of Andre Agassi, former professional tennis player and ATP number one, told from his own perspective.
Takeaways Andre Agassi played professional tennis from 1986 to 2006 and won eight Grand Slam single championships. He grew up under a dominant farther obsessed with tennis and the success of his children. Andre rose to fame early and struggled for a long time to find out who he was and what he stood for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Squares and Sharps, Suckers and Sharks</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_squares_sharps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:30:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_squares_sharps/</guid>
      <description>Author Joseph Buchdahl
Summary An analysis of the science, psychology and philosophy of gambling.
Takeaway Gambling is the speculation on the future that can take on different forms such as casino games, sports betting, and financial investing. Outcomes in these areas are hard to predict and it is even harder to make money from it against benchmarks that encapsulate the collective information of large crowds. Gamblers often underestimate the randomness that determine gambling outcomes and attribute positive outcomes to their own ability to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Can&#39;t Hurt Me</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 12:11:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</guid>
      <description>Author David Goggins
Summary The personal story of former Navy SEAL David Goggins who overcame traumatic experiences to become a successful soldier and athlete.
Takeaways Most people do not know what they are truly capable of and resist challenging themselves physically and mentally to stretch the limits of their potential.
Unlocking this potential requires hard work and dedicated exposure to uncomfortable experiences and pain to &amp;ldquo;callous&amp;rdquo; the mind and become mentally strong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
