<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 15:23:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Principles for dealing with the changing world order</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_changing_world_order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 15:23:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_changing_world_order/</guid>
      <description>Author Ray Dalio
Summary A historical account of the rise and fall of empires and the reasons behind them.
Takeaways History is repeating itself in well-defined cycles that determine the world order and the relationship of countries. Empires and dynasties rise and decline in a Big Cycle that is driven by universal cause and effect relationships that are in turn determined by fundamental characteristics of human nature such as fear, greed, jealousy, and other basic emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Party</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:39:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_party/</guid>
      <description>Summary A historical analysis of the working mechanisms of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP)
Takeaways The Chinese Communist Party (CCP) has been the sole legitimate governing authority in China since 1949. By the end of 2009 when the book was published, the CCP had 78 million members.
The Party consists of a giant network of people that are involved in every important decision and its members have built up the skills and experience to run the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Anarchy</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 19:27:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Author William Dalrymple
Summary The history of the rise and fall of the East India Company.
Takeaways The East India company was a trading company based in London that rose from humble beginnings to a fully fledged imperial power that managed to replace the ruling Mughal empire on the Indian subcontinent in a short period of time between 1756 and 1803. In that time period the East India Company extended their sphere of influence through treachery, forged contracts, collaboration with local banker, bribes, and military prowess in armed conflicts and wars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: 21 things you may not know about the Indian Act</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_indian_act/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 14:44:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_indian_act/</guid>
      <description>Author Bob Joseph
Summary A sample of 21 of the destructive and damaging statues and policies that constitute the Indian Act.
Takeaways The Indian Act, passed in 1876, regulated and still regulates the lives of Indigenous Peoples in Canada. One of the most damaging and destructive parts of the act was the introduction of residential schools that forced children to move away from their families and forbade them to speak their home language and practice their traditional religion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
