<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 20:32:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Algorithmic Leader</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_algorithmic_leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 20:32:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_algorithmic_leader/</guid>
      <description>Author Mike Walsh
Summary Anecdotes about modern leaders and their approach to decision making.
Takeaways We experience a time of accelerated change that is unlikely to slow down in the future. With new technologies emerging and more data being available to influence decision making, leaders need to adjust their way of approaching problems. For example, successful leaders in the &amp;ldquo;algorithmic age&amp;rdquo; apply first principles thinking to come up with solutions that can be carried out by computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Think Like a Freak</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_think_like_a_freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 21:30:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_think_like_a_freak/</guid>
      <description>Author Stephen J. Dubner und Steven Levitt
Summary A collection of stories that illustrate how to think more productively, creatively, and rationally.
Takeaways People have difficulties thinking rationally. They have biases that leads them to seek evidence that confirms what they already think, or are tempted to adopt views of friends, families, and colleagues.
&amp;ldquo;Thinking like a freak&amp;rdquo; means to get comfortable with admiting to not know the answer to a question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Decision Making Under Deep Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_dmdu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 11:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_dmdu/</guid>
      <description>Author Vincent A. W. J. Marchau, Warren E. Walker, Pieter J. T. M. Bloemen, Steven W. Popper
Summary A review of methods and applications for decision making under deep uncertainty.
Takeaways Situations with deep uncertainty are characterized by a lack of knowledge about how future events will unfold. In complex systems, the predictability of potential outcomes is low.
When confronted with deep uncertainty, decision makers are advised to shift from a predict-then-act paradigm to a monitor-and-adapt strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Noise: A Flaw in Human Judgment</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 10:26:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_noise/</guid>
      <description>Author Daniel Kahneman, Olivier Sibony, Cass R. Sunstein
Summary A summary of decision hygiene practices to reduce noise in judgments.
Takeaways Noise is ubiquitous in situations that require judgment and leads to unwanted and costly variability and unfairness in decisions. The reasons for noise in judgments are manifold. People have cognitive biases and a natural preference for causal thinking that finds comfort in finding coherent explanations even if the reality is more complex and less predictable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Agile Data Science 2.0</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_agile_data_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 16:58:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_agile_data_science/</guid>
      <description>Author Russel Jurney
Summary Instructions for a technical setup to iteratively develop practical Data Science applications.
Takeaways Many Data Science applications fail because of a missing feedback loop between the Data Scientists developing the solutions and the business stakeholders and users. To avoid a disconnect, Data Scientists need to share work in progress frequently. Software development methodolodies like Scrum need to be adapted to account for the larger uncertainty of data exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Nudge</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_nudge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 09:29:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_nudge/</guid>
      <description>Author Richard H. Thaler, Cass R. Sunstein
Summary Practical recommendations for how to design systems that support people in making the right choices.
Takeaways The design of the environment in which choices have to be made (choice architecture) often greatly influences the results, e.g. the order of food items in a cafeteria or the order of options and default values on a website. The goal of designing choice architectures should be to nudge people to make a choice that best reflects their true intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Made to stick</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_made_to_stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 14:25:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_made_to_stick/</guid>
      <description>Author Chip Heath, Dan Heath
Summary An overview of communication techniques for effective messaging of ideas.
Takeaways In order for ideas to stick with an audience they have to be framed as Simple Unexpected Concrete Credible Emotional Stories (SUCCES). If we follow the SUCCES framework, we can drill to the core of the message to know what to say (simple) and frame it in a way that helps people to pay attention (unexpected), understand and remember (concrete), believe and agree (credible), care (emotional), and act (stories).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The goal</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>Author Eliyahu M. Goldratt
Summary The story of a plant manager who discovers the benefit of systematically assessing the processing bottlenecks instead of relying on conventional wisdom.
Takeaways Instead of relying on conventional wisdom, it is crucial to deeply reflect on the goal of an operation or organization and take a scientific and systematic approach to explore the factors (bottlenecks or constraints) that prevent us from reaching it.
The following process can serve as a blueprint to work towards achieving any goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Weapons of math destruction</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 19:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_weapons_of_math_destruction/</guid>
      <description>Author Cathy O&amp;rsquo;Neil
Summary A warning of the destructive power of black-box algorithms that govern our lives.
Takeaways Algorithms and mathematical models are ubiquitously applied and drive decisions in every aspect of our lives. They, for example, determine college admissions, calculate insurance fees, and determine the content in our social media feeds. Many of the algorithms are intransparent, making it impossible to understand and challenge the results. If there is no alignment between the objectives of the models and the interest of the modeled subjects and if there is no feedback loop to improve the model over time, these &amp;ldquo;weapons of math destruction (WMD)&amp;rdquo; can cause significant harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Factfulness</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:26:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Author Hans Rosling
Summary A plea to overcome the human instincts that prevent us from developing a fact based worldview.
Takeaways Knowledge of global patterns and trends is poor across demographics even though data is publicly available. Common assumptions about topics like population growth, income inequality, education and health, are not only wrong but are systematically distorted. Developments appear more negatively than they are. Reasons are a lack of statistical literacy and our instincts to generalize, blame others, and consider things without appropriate comparison frames and proportions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: A brief history of everyone who ever lived</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_brief_history_everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 12:36:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_brief_history_everyone/</guid>
      <description>Author Adam Rutherford
Summary A scientific view of the role that DNA plays in understanding human history, and what we can and cannot conclude when analyzing it.
Takeaways Depicting our ancestry looks more like an entagled mesh than a tree. Everyone living today shares the same group of ancestors if we go back long enough in time.
DNA influences observable characteristics in a probabilitic way. There are only a few genes that have a clear physical manifestation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
