<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 12:11:59 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Can&#39;t Hurt Me</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 12:11:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_cant_hurt_me/</guid>
      <description>Author David Goggins
Summary The personal story of former Navy SEAL David Goggins who overcame traumatic experiences to become a successful soldier and athlete.
Takeaways Most people do not know what they are truly capable of and resist challenging themselves physically and mentally to stretch the limits of their potential.
Unlocking this potential requires hard work and dedicated exposure to uncomfortable experiences and pain to &amp;ldquo;callous&amp;rdquo; the mind and become mentally strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Factfulness</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:26:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_factfulness/</guid>
      <description>Author Hans Rosling
Summary A plea to overcome the human instincts that prevent us from developing a fact based worldview.
Takeaways Knowledge of global patterns and trends is poor across demographics even though data is publicly available. Common assumptions about topics like population growth, income inequality, education and health, are not only wrong but are systematically distorted. Developments appear more negatively than they are. Reasons are a lack of statistical literacy and our instincts to generalize, blame others, and consider things without appropriate comparison frames and proportions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
