<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Notes</title>
    <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:20:50 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/books/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book: Project Hail Mary</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_hail_mary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:20:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_hail_mary/</guid>
      <description>Author Andy Weir
Summary The story of a high school teacher and former molecular biologist sent on a space mission to save humanity from becoming extinct.
Takeaways Breakthroughs can be made quickly when the scientific community works together towards a common goal and is unobstructed from political interference and misaligned incentives. Faced with an extential threat, the human habitants of earth combine resources and consolidate power to streamline the successful execution of project Hail Mary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The goal</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:27:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_the_goal/</guid>
      <description>Author Eliyahu M. Goldratt
Summary The story of a plant manager who discovers the benefit of systematically assessing the processing bottlenecks instead of relying on conventional wisdom.
Takeaways Instead of relying on conventional wisdom, it is crucial to deeply reflect on the goal of an operation or organization and take a scientific and systematic approach to explore the factors (bottlenecks or constraints) that prevent us from reaching it.
The following process can serve as a blueprint to work towards achieving any goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Mortal Engines</title>
      <link>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_mortal_engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 20:11:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jensadamczak.github.io/notes/posts/book_mortal_engines/</guid>
      <description>Author Philip Reeve
Summary The fictional tale of traveling cities and their residents that battle for survival in a distant future.
Takeaways Devotion to an ideology can be a strong motivator but also a destructive force. The actions of the characters are driven by their dedication to their way of living and their role in a world that leaves little room for exploring alternative ideas.
Quotes &amp;ldquo;But he mustn&amp;rsquo;t feel sorry for them: it was natural that cities ate towns, just as the towns ate smaller towns and smaller towns snapped up the miserable static settlements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
